你好黑客
hello hackers
欢迎来到PWN学院面向返回编程模块的第三个视频
welcome to the 3rd video in the return oriented programming module of pwn college
我是Yan，我将和大家谈谈ROP技术
I'm Yan and I will be talking to you about ROP techniques
这将是一场盛宴
this is going to be a smorgass board of
涵盖理论、技巧和建立ROP链的建议
concepts techniques and hints for successfully creating ROP chains
我们将从一个大家都很好奇的问题开始
and we will start with a not a proplem but a common thing that people wonder
创建shellcode时在哪里存储数据
where do I store data when you create shellcode
你的shellcode需要打开/flag文件
you and your shellcode needs to open the slash flag file
通常将/flag字符串放在shellcode的末尾
you often put the slash flag string at the end of your shellcode
你可以使用rip相关指令，比如LEA
and you use a rip relative instruction such as load effective address
RIP加偏移来将寄存器指向flag
rip plus whatever to point a register at that flag
这在shellcode中是常见的
was the common in the shellcode
ROP和这其实很相似
it's actually something very similar right
当你触发shellcode
when you're triggering shellcode
或者用ROP
or in a ropchain
不好意思，当你触发ROP链时
sorry when you're triggering a ropchain
覆盖了栈
you overwrite the stack
你可以将数据写入栈
you can write data onto that stack
诀窍是如果你把数据写入栈
the trick is if you write data onto the stack
你得小心别返回
you have to be careful not to return
不要将该数据视为ROP返回地址链的一部分
not to treat that data as a return address as part of your ropchain
这是一个潜在的ROP链
so here's a potential ropchain
你入栈一个gadget的地址
that you push the the address of a gadget
假设它会pop RDI
that will let's say pop RDI so
或者pop RSI之类的
or pop RSI or something
这是/flag
so this is you know slash flag
它将弹出/flag的地址
it will pop the address of slash flag
问题是
the proplem is
地址指向它右边第2个gadget
the address was actually as 2 gadgets to the right
gadget 1 可能返回到实际上第二个gadget（图上标的3）
your 1st gadget might return into what is actually your 2nd gadget
这个gadget是专门放在那里
which is a gadget that you will exclusively keep there
用来跳过这个gadget来到gadget4
to jump over this gadget to return to gadget 4
这样你就不会不小心跳入这里
so that you don't accidentally return to
将flag视为返回地址
treat flag as a return address
并尝试跳转到内存地址，小端序的, galf/
and try to jump to memory that is in little Endian g a l f forward slash
这个地址可能没有映射，程序就会崩溃
which likely isn't mapped and your program will crash
这里的/bin/cat也是一样的道理
and is the same idea for bin cat as well
怎么跳过去?
how do you do this sort of jumping over
我们将使用我称之为
we'll use what I call
它们没有标准的名称
there's no standard name for them
我称之为清洁gadget
but what I call janitorial gadgets
这些gadget可以修复你的ROP链
a lot of gadgets are there to fix up your ROP chain
如果你在选项（从程序中找的gadgets）中夹杂数据
if you have data interspersed into your option
或者你对程序的溢出操作
or if the program that you are overflowing
破坏了部分选项
actually corrupt part of your option
你可能得跳过损坏的部分
you might have to jump over corrupted parts
有很多rop链可以做到这一点
there are plenty of ropchains that will do that
如果有你不关心的寄存器
if there are registers that you don't care about
不在意
that you don't mind collaboring with
之前在栈上写入了什么数据
whatever data you have  on this stack that you have written to the stack
你只需触发这些
you just trigger these
将栈上数据pop到寄存器的ROP gadget
something like a rop gadget that pops data to those registers
在上个视频我们演示的简单rop-example中
in the simple rop-example that we ran through last video
我们在
we had in the
在反汇编中
in the disassembly
在foo函数中打开了/flag
in the foo function where we triggeret the open slash flag
之后，它pop了RBP
afterwards it popped RBP
那时我们在payload中放的垃圾
and we put garbage there
但是我们可以把数据放在那里
but we could have put data there
在4011C2的这个gadget
that this gadget at 401 1C2
如果我们跳到那里，它会弹出RBP，然后返回
if we jump there it will pop RBP and ret
我们不需要执行这些打开等等发送
we don't have to do the open et cetera send er
我们可以把它用作栈清理工具
we can just use this as a stack clean up gadget
用来跳过栈上8字节的垃圾
to just jump over 8 bytes of garbage on the stack
这很酷
which is super cool
类似地，有很多gadget可以清理栈帧
similarly there's a lot of gadgets that will clean up a stack frame
释放栈帧的一部分
deallocate a part of a stack frame
如果你分配了40字节
so if you had allocated 40 bytes
十六进制40个字节到栈帧上
or hex 40 bytes onto a stack frame
可能有一个gadget会在返回时释放40字节
there's likely a gadget that will subtract 40 byte from ret
也是超级酷的
which is super cool as well
抱歉
or sorry
减去40字节，再加上re
subtract 40 bytes add re
让我重新开始
let me start that over
如果你找到一个函数
if there's a function that you find
它的栈帧有40字节
that has a stack frame of 40 bytes in the beginning of the function
在函数开头会将rsp减去0x40
and likely subtracts hex 40 from RSP
在函数结束的时候，它会把它加回去
and at the end of the function it will add that back on
你可以重用它作为跳过垃圾的gadget
and you can reuse that as a you know skip over garbage gadget
另一个ROP概念
another rop concept
如何将值存储到寄存器中
how do you store values into your registers
你可以使用 pop值到寄存器的 gadget
well you can use register popping gadgets
如果你想让RAX指向/flag
so if you want to point rax to slash flag
你可以找到一个gadget，它会执行pop rax然后ret
you find a gadget that says that does pop rax ret
它们确实存在，但不是很常见
these exist they're not super common
通常它们也有其他副作用
usually they have other side effects as well
然后放上那个gadget
and then you put that gadget
那个gadget的地址
that address of that gadget
然后是想要弹出到RAX中的值
then the desire value you want to get popped into RAX
当你回到这个gadget
when you return to this gadget
你会用这个gadget覆盖返回地址
you'll of course overwrite the return address with this gadget and
Pop rax会执行。它会弹出这个，执行ret
pop rax will run. it'll pop this ret will run
然后跳转到gadget2
and jump to gadget 2
它会清除栈中的/flag
in this case it'll presumably clean up slash flag off the stack
很好，嗯
cool alright um
另一个概念
another concept
有些gadget比其他的更常见
some gadgets are more common than others
最常见的gadget是ret
the most common gadget is ret
它在每个函数的末尾都有
it's at the end of every function
实际上有一个gadget
and actually has a gadget on its own
它很有用
it is useful
你可能还记得shellcode中nop雪橇的概念
you might recall the concept of a nop sled in shellcode
在ROP链中有一种东西叫做ret雪橇
well in ropchains there's something called a ret sled
他俩非常非常相似
very very similar
如果你放一堆ret gadget来溢出栈
if you just put a bunch of ret gadgets to overflow the stack
只要其中一个溢出了返回地址
as long as one of them overflows the return address
都会ret，ret，ret
you will then ret ret ret ret ret ret ret
一直ret到你真正的ROP
ret ret ret all the way to your actual ropchain
类似于nop雪橇
similar to a nop sled
嗯，leave ret也是一个很常见的gadget
um leave ret is a very common gadget as well
在许多函数的末尾都有
at the end of many functions
如果你破坏了RBP，你必须小心
you have to be careful if you have corrupted RBP
因为当执行leave时
and you do leave
也会破坏RSP
you will corrupt RSP as well
leave指令实际执行了mov rsp rbp 和 pop rbp
leave does move RSP RBP; pop RBP
所以你要确保RBP指向一个有意义的地址
so you want to make sure that RBP is pointing to an address that makes sense
另一个常见的gadget是
another relatively common very common gadget is
pop寄存器，然后ret
pop some register and then ret
这在返回前恢复被调用者保存的寄存器时尤其明显
this is especially seen when restoring callee saved registers before returning
这非常频繁
it is very frequent
它可能修改很多寄存器
and it's it's seen for a wide variety of registers
甚至可以看到它修改RAX
sometimes you even see it for RAX where you
也许没有pop RAX，但有给RAX赋值
maybe you don't pop RAX but you move something to RAX
然后返回
and then return
这就是在设置函数的返回值
that is setting a return value of a function
有些gadget很常见
some gadgets are common
因为这些功能在程序中很常见
because  the functionality is pretty common in a binary
比如leave ret或者pop某些寄存器，然后ret
like leave ret or pop some certain registers and ret
但是你可以跳到指令中间
but you can jump again into the middle of an instruction
这意味着,某些gadget是常见的
this means that certain gadgets are common
是因为其他gadget是常见的
because there are other common gadgets
后者的字节码包含了前者
that contain the bytes that encode those instructions right on
一个简单的例子
a trivial example
让我把相机藏起来，这样你就能看到了
let me disappear my camera so you can see
例子是：每个add rsp, 8; ret指令
the trivial example is that every gadget of add RSP 8 ret
这是一个相对的
which is a relatively
我的意思是很常见的gadget
I mean conceptually common
毕竟这类释放栈帧的操作很常见
this sort of deallocation of the stack frame
都包含了一个add ESP,8; ret gadget
also contains an add ESP 8 ret gadget
如果你跳过H前缀
if you jump past that H prefix again
这个H前缀你现在可能已经知道了
that H prefix you are propably by now
非常痛苦地意识到就是它决定了是对ESP、EAX等的操作
very painfully aware is what changes operations on ESP and EAX and so forth
还是对 RSP、RAX等的操作
to RSP rax and so forth
一般来说，指令的字节数越长
in general the longer the instruction in bytes
它在二进制中出现的次数越少
the more rare it will randomly appear in a binary
但是某些很长的指令
but certain instructions even long ones
会因为频繁使用而频繁出现
will appear frequently because they are frequently used
好吧
all right
另一个概念
another concept
如何将地址存储到寄存器中
how do you store addresses into registers
这些地址你可能......
addresses you might not otherwise have
我提到过
I known I mentioned that
长指令不太可能随机出现
long instructions are less likely to randomly appear
LEA就是这样一条指令
load effective address is one such instruction
这条指令很长
that instruction is very long
你很少看到它出现在ROP gadget中
so it's rare that you will see that instruction as part of a rop gadget
但它可能出现在二进制程序中
it might be in the binary
LEA指令通常在函数的开头
but the load effects address instructions are usually at the beginning of a function
但你通常期望的都在函数末尾
and you typically want things at the end of functions
要把这些gadget链起来
to chain these gadgets
你要做的是
what you might instead do is
通常很怪的gadget，由跳到指令中间产生的
gadgets usually really weird gadgets resulting from jumping part way into an instruction
会push rsp，pop Rax，然后返回
that does stuff push the stack pointer pop Rax and then return
这将把rsp赋值给rax
so this will move RSB rax essentially
还有更危险的
there are more dangerous ones
等等，等等
wait wait wait
等一下，我刚刚改了没生效，马上回来
hold on I made a type on the slide I'll be right back
我们回来了，很抱歉
and we're back sorry about that
得把这个幻灯片修好
had to fix up this slide
好了,那么
alright so
LEA不好，它很长
load effective address is not good it's very long
它相较函数不常见
it's not often found than the functions
你通常需要一个更好的选择
you typically need a better alternative
有几种不同的方法
there are a couple of different ways
这些方法是非常看情况的
these things are very situational
取决于你能使用的gadget
depends on the gadgets available to you
替补1
alternative one
它将push RSP;pop RAX并返回
something that will push RSP pop RAX and return
这将把rsp赋值给rax
this will move RSP into RAX
你能通过它拿到栈。当然，RSP仍然完好无损
you get the stack at it. of course RSP remains intact
替补2是add RAX, RSP
another alternative is to add RAX, RSP
如果你以某些方式pop 0到RAX中
this will if you pop 0 into RAX in some other way
这将把RSP赋值给RAX
then this will move RSP into RAX
否则RAX会是一个相对RSP旧RAX偏移的地址
otherwise it could offset RAX by RSP
但从概念上讲，它也算将RSP的值传给了RAX
but conceptually it still gets the value of RSP somehow into RAX
一条疯狂的路线是一条叫做交换的指令
a crazy route is an instruction called exchange
它在二进制中作为gadget经常出现，
that actually shows up in binaries relatively frequently as a rop gadget
它将交换寄存器rax和RSB的值，然后返回
that will swap registers rax and RSB and then return
这是非常危险的
this is insanely dangerous
我将在下一行解释为什么
I'll go into why that is on the next line
但基本思路是，如果你可以在程序中用gadget
but the basic idea is if you can use gadgets in the program
获取地址，计算地址等等
to get addresses and compute addresses and so forth
你需要的数据泄露漏洞会更少
you might need fewer leaks of fewer data disclosure of vulnerabilities
否则你可能需要执行完整端到端攻击（否则更麻烦）
then you otherwise might need to actually perform end to end attack
所以
so
我提到了xchg RAX RSP是危险的
I mentioned exchange RAX RSP is dangerous right
如果你不喜欢你的栈
if you don't like your stack
有很多原因导致你不喜欢你的栈
and there are many reasons why you might not like your stack
例如，你的栈可能过于受限
for example your stack might be too limiting
你可能无法读取足够的数据来溢出
you might not be able to read enough data to actually overflow
或者你可能无法溢出足够的数据
or you might not be able to overflow enough data
来获得一个足够长的ROP链
to have a long ROP chain a long enough ROP chain
你可以试试stack pivot
um you can try a stack pivot
这个xchg rax,RSP会交换rax和RSP的值
so this exchange rax RSP will swap rax and RSP
当下一次返回时
when the next ret happens
这个将被弹出的返回地址是
this a return address will be popped off
你的新栈
of what is now your new stack
也就是以前RAX指向的地址
which is where rax used to point
当你做这个交换时，你最好确定
you better make sure when you do this exchange rax RSP
RAX指向了一个合法的地址
that rax is pointing to something reasonable
还有一些相对更常见的gadget
there are also gadgets that show up relatively frequently
它们会pop RSP
that do pop RSP
概念上有点相似
kind of conceptually similar
通常情况下，他们是某些指令的一部分
usually it's they are misaligned into a part of an instruction
这个是pop RSP，然后是一些其他的东西，然后是ret
so it's pop RSP and then some other stuff and then a ret
好吧
all right
注意stack pivot
be careful about stack pivot
但如果你走投无路，它会是一个强大的工具
but it can be a powerful tool  if your back is against the wall
否则
otherwise
另一个重要的概念是如何传输数据
um another rop concept how do you transfer data
像传入传出内存
like to memory and from memory
嗯
um
这些gadget出奇地普通
a gadget that is weirdly common are these
或者说是一组gadget
or a group of gadgets is
向al添加一个字节的内存
add a byte of memory to al
pop RBP ret
我猜
I'm guessing
这是某指令序列中的部分
this is some sort of a misaligned part of an instruction sequence
这在函数末尾很常见
that is common at the end of functions
其实我并没有仔细研究过
I hadn't actually looked into it
一个缺点是，这通常需要
one downside is this typically requires
这的确需要一个gadget来设置我们的RCX和al
or this does require a gadget to set our RCX  and to set al
设置RCX的gadget非常罕见
gadgets to set RCX for whatever reason are surprisingly rare
这可能不是最优的，但是
so this might not be optimal but
你可以搜索类似的gadget来存储内存
you can search for similar gadgets to store memory
重点是有gadget可以储存内存
the point is there are gadgets that will store memory
如今，在ROP中构建复杂存储结构的情况已经不常见了
nowadays it's much less common in a ropchain to need to build complex memory structures
因为我们不再在栈上传递参数等等
because we no longer pass arguments on the stack and so forth
但有时确实会发生
but it does happen sometimes
有时候你一开始可以使用的ROP链非常有限
sometimes you are very limited by the ropchains you can use initially
然后你必须建立一个副ROP链存储器
and then you have to build a secondary ropchain memory
使用类似这样的工具
using something like this
但这是一种少见的情况
but but it's kind of an exotic thing
你可能不会做太多的数据存储
you likely won't do much data storage
然后再在你的ROP链中读取内存
and and retrieval in memory in your ropchain
好吧
alright
另一个ROP概念
another rop concept
系统调用指令
the syscall instruction
这在shellcode中非常常见
which you are very used to in shellcode
在ROP中很少见
is actually very rare in rop
通常需要调用库函数
typically you will need to call library functions
如果你注意到
if you notice
在我们的例子中
in our example
我们有
we had
我们调用foo的一部分，它调用了一个open
we called part of foo which did an open
这是一个库函数
this is a library function
我们执行了bar的一部分
we did part of bar
这
which did a
我弄丢了
I lost it
这执行了sendfile
which did sendfile
也是一个库函数
also library function
库函数是通过二进制文件中的一个特殊部分调用的
library functions are called through a special part of the binary
称为过程链接表plt
called the procedure linkage table
所以如果你看401070
so if you look at 401070
在这里
up here
在PLT
in the PLT
这里是401070
here is 401070
是sendfile
it's send file
它做了很多复杂的事情
and it does a bunch of complex stuff
在libc中查找sendfile的地址并跳转到那里
to look up the address of sendfile in libc and jump there
这可能是另一个视频或问答的主题
this will likely be the subject of another later video or extended Q&A
但是为了使用库函数
but in order to use library functions
你得知道他们在哪
you need to know where they are
这样你才能把它们的返回地址写到栈上
so you can write their return address onto the stack
或者用其他方式跳过去
or jump there in some other way
否则你最好希望
otherwise you better hope
二进制文件中就有一个系统调用指令
that there's a syscall instruction inside the binary
或者在二进制文件中有你要用函数所需的PLT条目
or a PLT entry inside the binary for the function you need
这有点棘手
it's a little tricky
我的建议是保持简单
my advice keep it simple
获得flag的最短路径是最简单的
the shortest path to your flag is easiest in this case
在我们的示例中，就是重用二进制文件中的open和sendfile
it was reusing open and sendfile in the binary in our example case
但如果你只有chown，也能成功
but if all you have is chown you can make that work
在前面的模块中
in the previous module
您已经使用单个系统调用执行了一个shellcode
you've carried out a shellcode with a single syscall
好吧
all right
另一个ROP概念
another rop concept
了解你的环境
know your environment right
你的ROP链不会在真空中开始执行
your ropchain doesn't just start executing in a vacuum
当你的ROP链启动
when your ropchain starts
它的状态有各种各样有用的信息
there's all sorts of useful information in the state
在shellcoding模块中
in the shellcoding module
我们有几个关卡
we had several levels where
你必须使用寄存器中已经为0的部分状态
you had to use part of the state that register that were already 0
这样你不需要把它们清零，等等
so you didn't have to 0 them out etc
这里也有类似的东西
there's similar things here
有地址指向代码、栈、堆和libc
there are addresses  that are pointing to code to the stack to the heap to libc
这些地址到处都是
all over the place
如果你需要这些地址
if you need one of those addresses
然后你可以在你的ROP链中检索和用它
then you can retrieve and reason about it in your ropchain
你不需要从头开始
you don't have to get it somehow from scratch
使用这些地址
use these addresses right
不要丢弃程序状态中的丰富信息
don't discard all of the rich information  that's in the program state
当你劫持了控制流程后
when you hijack control flow
我以前做过，每个人都做过
I've done that in the past everyone does
用了大量的时间
it waste an enormous amount of time
对自己好一点
do yourself a favor and
当你劫持控制流时，
when you hijack execution to begin with
先看看所有寄存器的值
look at the values of all the registers
看看栈的值
look at the value of the stack
看看里面有什么有用的
and see you know what in there you can use
好了终于
alright finally
我一直在说
I keep saying
你最好祈祷
you know you better hope
这个gadget是存在的。那个gadget是存在的
this rop gadget exists. that rop gadget is exist
怎么找gadget呢？
how do you find rop gadgets
当我刚开始的时候，这是一个纯手工活
when I 1st started out it was a manual process
当时有一种工具
believe it or not there was one tool
它是为Windows设计的
it was for windows
我记得它是收费的
and I don't think it was free
这是个坏消息
and it was just bad news
但是现在有非常多的工具
but now there are tools all over the place
我维护了一堆CTF工具的安装程序
I maintain a bunch of installers for CTF tools
仅仅这个仓库就有3个不同工具的安装程序
and just that repository has installers for 3 different tools
用来找rop gadget的工具
that people have written to find rop gadget
我将向你展示一个这样的工具
I'll show you one such tool
它叫做RP + +
it is called RP plus plus
用起来很简单，只要执行RP + +
very easy you do RP plus plus
默认情况下，它将打印出来
by default it'll print out
在程序的不同位置的可能重复的gadget
a bunch of duplicate gadgets at different positions in the program
这可能对你有用
this might be useful to you
如果你的输入有限制，但这种情况很少
in case there's constraints on your input but propably not
告诉它这个gadget应该有多深
tell it how deep the gadget should be
指令有多长
how many instructions long
2是个好数字，你可以要求更多，但是
2 is a good number you can do more than 2 but
它增加了gadget产生一些疯狂效果的可能
there it increases the chance that your gadget will have some crazy effects
而且可能无法修复
that you might not be able to compensate for
这可能会使你的程序崩溃
that might make your program crash
然后给它一个文件
and then you give it a file
我们给它rop_example
and so let's give our rop example
这些是rop_example中的gadget
these are the gadgets in our rop example file
50个独特的gadget。并不多
50 unique gadgets not a lot
好了，我们有两个
alright we have 2 of these
add RSP 8; ret
这是栈清理和返回
so this is some stack cleanup and a return
我提到过，每个add RSP指令去掉首字节就是add ESP指令
I mentioned that at every add RSP one byte into it is an add ESP
所以在401016有一个add rsp
so there's an add RSP at 401016
就有一个add ESP 在 401017
and an add ESP at 401017
为什么，因为它正好跨越了那个H
why because it jumps right past that H
H把add ESP变成add RSP
and the H turns it from add ESP to add RSP
还有一些疯狂的gadget
there's some crazy other gadget
这是我们之前讲过的那个leave ret
well here's that leave ret that we talked about
有很多ret,找到了14个
there's a lot of just ret 14 of them
到目前为止最常见的gadget
the most common gadget by far
有很多pop RDI
a lot of pop RDI
pop RSI pop R15
pop RSI and R15
RDI和RSI是函数前两个参数
so RDI and RSI those are the 1st 2 arguments
这已经很不错了
already that's pretty good
如果我们能找到清零RDX的方法
if we can figure out a way to zero out RDX
然后
then
基本上就可以
if you're basically good to go to
就可以调用系统调用了
and and figure out a way to trigger system calls
我们就准备好了
and we're good to go
当然在这个程序中有很多
but of course in this program there're quite
有些之前用过的好用的大的gadget
there're very nice big gadgets that we used earlier
你会注意到我们用来打开和发送文件的gadget
so you'll notice that the gadgets that we used to open and send files
在这里并没有
don't show up here
对于rp++来说它们太大太复杂了
they're way too big way too complex for rp plus plus reason about
所以依赖这些自动工具并不总是值得的
so it doesn't always pay to depend on these automatic tools
如果你试一下更大的二进制文件，比如bin bash
if you do a bigger binary something like bin bash
这里什么都有
there's everything in here right
成堆成堆成堆成堆成堆的gadget
tons and tons and tons and tons and tons of gadgets
同样，这些是错位的指令
and again these are misaligned instructions
他们就像
they're like
可能是各种各样的东西
it could be all sorts of stuff
实际上可能没有这样的东西
there might not actually be something like this
二进制中不太可能有这样的东西
it's unlikely that there's something like this in the binary
估计是跳转到指令中的部分
we propably jump part away through an instruction
或者可能有，但是不管怎样
or there there could be actually but anyways
但是这里有很多东西
but there's a lot of stuff
我想提一件事，然后展示给你们看
and I wanted to mention one thing and then show it to you
实际上，当你有了这个gadget列表
realistically once you have that list of gadgets
某些人会尝试这样做
certain gadget chain searchers can try to
某些gadget的发现者也可以尝试
or certain gadget finders can also try to
用这些gadget构建ROP链
build chains out of your gadgets
用类似于pwntools自动生成shellcode的方法
doing that is similar to generating shellcode automatically pwntools
这在某些情况下是可行的
it'll work for some cases
但是当它不起作用的时候
but when it doesn't work
这会浪费你大量的时间
it'll waste enormous amounts of your life
你应该能
you should be competent in
使用正则表达式在输出中搜索目标gadget
searching through the output for your gadgets using regular expressions
如果你想
so let's say if you wanted to
找到一个可以设置RDX的gadget
find a gadget that will set RDX
所以你可以grep -P
so you can grep dash capital P
启用所有perl正则表达式扩展(pcre)
enables all the perl regular expression extensions
我们可以找一下
and we can say okay let's find something
mov,add,sub或pop RDX
either move or add or sub or pop RDX
这少的有点离谱
there's shockingly little
RDX是一个棘手的问题
RDX is a tricky one
这是一个很好
so here this is a good one
这是 pop RDX
so this pops RDX
当然这是在bin bash中，而不是在我们的小程序里
this is of course in bin bash not in our tiny program
pop RDX; or EAX, 数字
pops RDX or EAX with some large numbers
所以我们必须恢复EAX
so we'll have to restore EAX
我们必须时刻注意副作用
we have to constantly fight against side effect
然后返回，这很好
and return so that's great
另一个是add RDX RCX
another one is this add RDX RCX
之后会直接跳转到RDX
but then we have to jump right to RDX
这可能不太好
that's propably not good
是的，这些是
yeah so these are
这个可能是对我们最好的
this one is propably the best for us
同样，如果你想找一个可以写内存的gadget
likewise if you want to find a gadget that you can write to memory with
你可以这样做
you can do something like this
用英特尔汇编风格写入内存
writing to memory in proper Intel assembly
你执行你需要操作然后是要用的内存大小
you do your operation and your memory size
所以我们可以
and so we can say okay
有一个mov，然后是一个单词，然后是一个左括号
there's a move then a word and then an open bracket
这里是我们可以用来影响内存的各种方式
and here all of the various ways we can influence memory
这是一个很好的例子
and so here's a good one
将4B从DX移至RSI指向的内存
move 4B to RSI from DX
是的，所以这可能是一个很好的例子
yeah so this is propably a good one
因为我刚找到了设置RDX的方法
because I just found how to set RDX
如果你找到如何设置RSI
now if you find how to set RSI
对于RSI，我也是这么做的
I do the same for RSI
RSI很容易设置
RSI is easy to set
这个
there's right
RSI在这里很难设置
RSI is shockingly difficult to set here
我是不是说错了
am I full of crap
我说错了
I am full of crap
嗯，是的
um yeah so
在这种情况下，RSI实际上不容易设置
in this case RSI is actually not easy to set
我们该如何设置RSI
how would we set RSI
我们得用像这样的东西
we would have to use something like this
但我们必须挺过这个对R13的调用
but then we have to survive this call R13
所以现在我们要设置R13
so then we have to set R13
现在你知道可以有多绕了
now you can see how deep that rabbit hole can go
好吧
all right
就是这样
and that's it
这就是我们对这些更高级的rop概念的介绍
that is the end of our run through these more advanced rop concepts
你们将在整个模块中练习它们
you'll practice them of course throughout the module
在下个视频中
and in the next video
我们会讨论更多的复杂情况
we'll talk about complications even more complications